So, like, ever since Morishige
was dumped by Miura,
he's been texting Hiroko nonstop.
What? Ew.
I guess Matsuzaki is single now, too.
Oh, yeah. Hey, Tsubomi.
Wanna go to karaoke after school?
Huh? Uh, sorry, I'm actually
a bit under the weather.
I'll pass.
Huh? Really? You should hang out
with us every once in a while.
Oh, shit! Snot just exploded everywhere!
Come on. You don't have to
sing, so just come with us.
Maybe next time.
Hey, do you two have any tissues?
Nope.
I'm going to go throw this in the garbage,
so put the cleaning tools away for me.
We'll go with you. Let's walk slow
so we can kill some time.
Why are you covering your face?
Hm? Oh, no reason.
Wait, what is it? I'm so curious now.
Come on, move your hand!
O-Oh, no... If they see my
face covered in snot...
Wanna see a picture of Takane Tsubomi's
face just covered in snot from yesterday?
Ew, gross!
Oh, crap!
You can't be serious!
That's bound to happen.
Hey, you two...
The teacher was looking for you.
Ugh, lame.
Well, this sucks.
Wait, Tsubomi.
Sorry, now's not a good time.
Here you go. Some tissues.
Thank you so much, Mob.
Oh, sure.
You know, it's been a
while since we talked.
Yeah.
Thanks.
Well, I'll see you later.
See you later?!
(See you later)
Mob!
You got a second?
Mezato.
On Sunday night,
there's going to be a huge gathering
for the Psycho Helmet Religion.
Will you come?
Sorry, I'm just not interested.
Please! Just for a little bit!
Cough! Ahem...
Erm...
Tome.
Mob, do you realize you promised
you'd help me find telepathists on Sunday?
Oh, right...
Anyway, think it over.
I'll call your house.
Kageyama.
Emi? What brings you here?
I was just observing.
You're totally popular.
Way to go, Kageyama.
Sorry?
Oh, look at you playing dumb.
Popular? Me?
But you know... I did actually
talk to a lot of girls today.
And even though it wasn't for long,
I got to talk to Tsubomi alone, too.
Brother! Are you heading home?
Let's walk home together.
Ritsu...
Would you lend me your ear for a second?
What's up?
I...
might be getting popular...
Huh?
Er, sorry! Forget I ever said anything.
Uh, Brother!
I'm sure I just got the wrong idea again.
How embarrassing.
I-I'm being watched?
The girls passing by keep glancing at me?
Kageyama's so hot.
I'm not imagining it.
They're whispering as
they glance over at me.
Right? Ritsu's great and so refined.
Could it be... I'm right? No...
I'm definitely popular.
Shigeo's so hot.
(Hearing things)
(Mob on a high horse 100%)
Finally... Congrats, Nii-san.
(MOB MOB WOW!)
I realized that our youth is Grey
The origin of this uneasiness
Is yet unknown
Trains of emotions keep running
Through my brain
Struggling through this adolescence
Don't disturb my deep psyche
Who is that behind you?
Opposing ideas creates distortion
Exorcise all the sorrow
So, do what you can now
My life
Finally, break it down
(Want) Both greed
(Young) And honesty
(Burn) Are growing
(1) On this chest of mine
(Trance) I'm not waking up
(Chance) I want to wake up
(Stance) These two different faces of mine
(1) Are standing back-to-back
Taking things as it is
In this free relation where
We resent each other
Once these two become one
That smile becomes one
And only "1"
(MOB MOB WOW!)
"1"
One and only "1"
(MOB MOB WOW!)
"1"
One and only "1"
Is that the Divine Tree?
It's huge!
Let's take a picture!
Yeah!
Well? Isn't the view great?
It's lovely.
We're currently selling a roll cake
inspired by the Divine Tree.
It might even be lucky!
The Divine Tree is on our side.
It will answer our prayers!
The helix of life embraced by the earth...
We are nothing but tiny beings
of life says the Divine Tree.
When many desires and wishes gather in
one place, a new divinity is born.
This broccoli ended up becoming
the symbol of some god.
Its believers' energy of desire is colossal.
And with this energy, the Divine Tree
continues to grow even more.
However, this thing's just a huge broccoli
and has no power to actually lead the people.
So, I'll just take that
energy and put it to good use.
If this world needs a god so badly,
then I'll do the shepherding myself.
I'll produce a founder for the religious
organization missing theirs,
the Psycho Helmet Religion.
(Getting Carried Away
~100%~)
Shige, you've got a phone call.
It's a girl!
Hello?
Oh, Mezato.
So you want to talk about that one thing.
I keep telling you this,
but I'm not cut out for that.
Wait! Things really are changing, though.
Ever since the Divine Tree
showed up in our city,
a bunch of people have claimed to be the
founder of the Psycho Helmet Religion.
And now, they're going to hold an audition
to decide on the founder.
At this rate,
someone else is going to end up being
the founder of the Psycho Helmet Religion!
I can't let that happen!
That'd be so lame!
I'll call you back from my cellphone.
There are over 500,000 believers!
Wouldn't it be interesting if the founder
were a second-year middle school boy?
And you also happen to be a psychic!
That's so mysterious and cool!
I'm certain that'll make you
super popular with the girls.
Even with Takane, too!
Huh?
What's wrong?
Wait, Mezato, do you also...
Er, never mind.
What?
Anyway, what everyone needs isn't
some phony. It's you, Mob.
You need to come to founder audition, okay?
Everyone needs me...
Maybe it won't be so bad
to be the founder...
Well said, Shigeo!
Dimple?! You startled me.
I haven't seen you in a while.
What happened?
What happened? That's my line.
What's with the face and voice, man?
What happened?
I see.
You got the wrong idea because
she said, "See you later."
No, that's not a misunderstanding.
That's the truth.
Thinking that just because
you talked to a girl
happens all the time to prepubescent boys.
Those stares you think you're seeing
are also a misunderstanding.
Seriously, no one even notices you,
more than you can imagine.
Why would you say that? You weren't there.
I'm telling you this because
I care about you.
You're not actually popular right now.
What did you want, anyway?
Good question. Oh, right.
About the founder audition!
Huh? What about it?
You can't just sit there quietly, can you?
It's time to make our move!
This is our time to rise to the top!
Let's go together.
Why?
Huh?
This has nothing to do with you, Dimple.
But the predecessor to the
Psycho Helmet Religion, (LOL),
was created by me...
But you gathered people there by
brainwashing them, didn't you?
Apparently with the Psycho Helmet Religion,
everyone gathered on their own
and they're all having fun peacefully,
so getting in the way is bad.
B-But having a proficient
leader is important.
What those people want is someone
who has divine powers.
I know.
And that's why it can't be you, Dimple.
The one everyone is seeking is me,
not you, Dimple.
He's totally crarried away...
Please. You think you have the
power to control the masses?
I didn't say anything about
being their founder.
I know I'm not cut out for that.
And that's why
if you and I join forces,
a super-elite religion will be born!
Which means...
It'll be the inception of a new god!
So is this god you, Dimple?
Er...
What, exactly, do you want to do as god?
I haven't decided that yet...
But I'd probably end up with powers
beyond my wildest imagination.
Well, I'm not interested in power,
so I'm not going to be
able to help you out.
Wha... Are you trying to
keep me out of this?!
Keep this up, and some other
jackass is gonna take over!
They're gonna keep all of this
divine energy to themselves!
So the reason you're stronger now is you
stole some of the energy from the broccoli.
That's fine and all, but...
You're also trying to take
them over, too, aren't you?
No! I'm just... You see...
So what makes you different
from the other guys?
Dimple...
Why don't you give
your schemes a rest already?
Dimple.
Haven't seen you in a while...
(Spirits and Such Consultation Office)
(Saturday)
So how's night school going, Serizawa?
It's a bit nerve-racking,
but I think I'll make it through.
I've sort of given up on making
friends, but I'll do my best.
What about you, Mob?
Anything interesting lately?
Yes, sort of...
What is it? Tell us already.
It's rare of you to ask us this
yourself, Master Reigen.
There's so little going on
that I'm bored out of my mind.
I mean, look at these jobs.
We've got like four requests to find out
if the sudden deterioration of some buildings
is due to some supernatural phenomena.
They must've gotten the wong idea
that we just do odd jobs.
I guess we don't just do odd jobs...
I don't have any other work for you
two today, so you can go home.
All right.
Oh, wait a sec.
That is, after I hear whatever interesting
thing is going on in your life, Mob.
What? You think you've finally
become popular lately?
Right. Welp, we're done for the day.
Good work, boys.
If you'll excuse me.
Oh, there's one other thing.
Tomorrow, I'll be attending a gathering
for some religious group.
Wha... Uh, are you okay with that?
I got invited.
Apparently, this group was formed
because of my actions,
so they want me to be their founder.
And are you going to be their founder?
I could if I wanted to... But I should
probably meet everyone first.
Good God, he's on a high horse.
Psycho... what was it again?
The Psycho Helmet Religion.
Oh, here we go.
Talk about half-assed...
Yikes, don't do it, Mob.
This is clearly shady as...
Hm?
580,000 believers?! It's that popular?!
They've even got monetary donations...
I-I...
smell a delicious business
opportunity here.
Go to that gathering!
A true man should be the founder of
a religious group at least once!
And!
Make sure you tell your believers
that you have a master, too!
Right...
So, what are you going to wear?
This is going to be your
time in the spotlight.
Huh?
Looks like they're going
to stream this online, too.
There's going to be hundreds of
thousands of people watching you.
What should I wear?
Stick out your hands, Mob.
Here's a bonus. Now go buy yourself
something nice to wear.
Master!
Thank you so much!
I'm here to shop for clothes,
but I have no idea what kind of clothes
to wear in the spotlight.
I guess I'll go home and talk to Ritsu...
Kageyama?
It is you!
Hanazawa!
I see. Well, leave that to me.
I know plenty of perfect shops.
That's great! Thanks!
I've been observing
what's going on in the city...
but I guess you've noticed it, too.
There's something gradually happening here.
No, wait...
Is there something going
on with those girls?
Well...
Lately, I feel like there are
a lot of girls staring at me.
I know I probably have the wrong
idea, but it's been on my mind.
Oho...
Kageyama...
That's not a misunderstanding.
You're just so cool that the girls
can't help but look your way.
No way. That can't be true...
That can't be true... or is it?
Aw, shucks.
Let's just leave it at that.
Come on. Let's get you some hip clothes.
Okay!
Hey, this will probably look good.
Oh, but this is above my budget.
I see.
Well, everything here is a bit pricey.
How about this? This is a super-popular
brand called Smart Monkey.
If possible, I'd like to keep
it under or at 5,000 yen.
Okay, I'm sure we'll find something.
Hm? Here we go!
This also has a monkey design
and it's 5,000 yen on the dot.
Yay! Let's go with that.
Thanks, Hanazawa-kun.
Nii-san...
Are you gonna go out wearing that?
Yup! Hanazawa helped me pick this out.
Right... I see.
Okay.
But you know...
I'm seeing Tome this afternoon,
and then Mezato tonight.
I'm so busy.
Tome's a bit late...
I was so worried that I just didn't
really get it in the end...
But is this shirt really that cool?
She's not answering her phone either.
I wonder if something happened to Tome.
Anyone auditioning, please head on in.
The emergence of the Divine Tree
is a message from the Earth.
The Divine Tree is the
legendary dragon's nest.
The Divine Tree is a sign
that nature is angry...
As if any of these shady religious organizations
can handle the true powers of the Divine Tree.
We, the Rising Sun Spiritual
Union, shall look after it.
Please speak of these
things further inside.
I'll walk you down.
There are so many people here.
The Psycho Helmet Religion
is partially a joke, right?
So where'd all these people come from?
There's not going to be a riot, is there?
Don't worry.
Let's believe in what he says.
In our founder who suddenly
showed himself yesterday.
And the one who speaks for the
Divine Tree, Psycho Helmet-sama.
We tried calling
the number you have dialed,
but the call cannot be completed.
Mezato-san's not answering...
She hasn't even told me
where everyone's meeting yet.
I guess I'll wait a little longer.
Yowch.
Mob sure is taking his time to appear.
Did he chicken out?
Oh, there he is.
Well, he seems pretty confident.
(Psycho Helmet Religion)
It's a pleasure to meet you, everyone.
I will be the one who will serve
as the founder of this religion,
Psycho Helmet.
What the hell? That's not Mob.
The hell's going on?
Damn it, his phone's out of battery.
But with the terrorist
attack the other day,
I have realized that we need
someone to protect this city.
From now on, I will be the one who
will lead everyone to happiness.
I plan to change this degenerate world
along with the Psycho Helmet Religion.
My battery's dead.
I am also the creator of the Divine Tree.
It is the symbol of the Psycho Helmet
Religion and its carefree nature.
The Divine Tree
grows with everyone's desires
and will bring the world happiness.
Please think of that tree as me
and continue praying to it.
Objection! The Divine Tree is the
egg in which the great Mossar-sama sleeps!
O Divine Tree! Please quell your rage!
That's also wrong! The Divine Tree
is the mecca for the Dragon's Sigh!
Psycho helmet, my ass! You fake religion!
-Yeesh...
That is a device that connects dimensions!
-Things are getting interesting.
Quit lying!
The Divine Tree will only bring about
happiness under our supervision!
I will now show you...
...a miracle.
Huh?!
It's a broccoli!
Bro...
What the heck just happened?!
The blue light shined
Dazzling my eye at 01:30 AM
Even as I swiped the page over,
The smiles of friends besides me remain
Yes, I want someone to understand
All the colorless and transparent wishes
All the breath stuck within
The depth of my heart
Suddenly flowed out
Bringing my consciousness back
I remember the days hung dry
The very normal days passed by
Even if reality is corrupted
The sky we saw together
Was definitely real
It's harder to understand than
The grammar on the blackboard
The story that disappears
Under 24 hours makes me sad and lonely
It's so hard, and I find myself
On the verge of giving up again and again
But I...
The current me will no longer give up
Overflowing emotions on my sleeve,
Running through worry and doubt
Nobody has decided
if the future is 0 or 100,
So I'll paint over them myself
Even if my existence itself
can't be proven,
If this world struck me in my heart
I will flood it with cobalt blue
This isn't good, Mob!
We're gonna be outta business
because of that broccoli!
Who cares if it's holy or popular?
We're gonna go destroy it!
Next time on Mob Psycho 100 III Episode 4:
"Divine Tree 1 ~The Founder Appears~"
A streaming service? But of course,
that's an excellent decision!